<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King wee haue since our entry into this realme of England, had special care to make all our subiects know, with how equall affection we resolued to proceede in all things which should concerne the safetie or honor of our kingdomes ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1603</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A21983</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8326</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S123928</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">33150750</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 33150750</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28738</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A21983)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28738)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1875:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King wee haue since our entry into this realme of England, had special care to make all our subiects know, with how equall affection we resolued to proceede in all things which should concerne the safetie or honor of our kingdomes ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
                  <author>James I, King of England, 1566-1625.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings most Excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1603.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>For equal execution of justice for English and Scots offenders.</note>
                  <note>Other title information from first 3 lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Contains historiated initial.</note>
                  <note>"Giuen at our Castle of Windsore the eight day of Iuly, 1603. in the first yeere of our Reigne of England, France, and Ireland, And of Scotland the sixe and thirtieth."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Equality before the law --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term>Justice, Administration of --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James I, 1603-1625.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:28738:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 9 -->
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the King.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Ee haue ſince our entry into this Realme of England, had ſpecial care</hi> to make all our Subiects know, with how equall affection we reſolued to proceede in all things which ſhould concerne the ſafetie or honor of our Kingdomes, for both which we know we are to make one and the ſelf-ſame accompt to Almighty God, vnder whom we hold all earthly things, In which reſpect, we were very curious to preuent at our firſt comming all manner of offences or affronts, which naturally doe ariſe betweene ſeuerall Nations at their firſt ioyning in ſocietie and conuerſation, neuer ceaſing to lay ſeuere commandement vpon our greateſt Subiects that came in with vs, to ſuppreſſe any iniurious Actions of any of their Seruants or Traine, towards the meaneſt Subiects of Engliſh birth, in whom from the higheſt to the loweſt we haue obſerued ſo great loue and generall obedience to vs and our Cammandements: And whenſoeuer it hath come to our eares that any Offence hath bene done by any of them, Wee haue made them know how much it hath diſpleaſed vs. Notwithſtanding, becauſe we doe heare of many Inſoelncies reported to be committed by our Nation of Scotland to our Engliſh Subiects, with this addition further, That the Magiſtrates and Iuſtices are thought to be remiſſe towards ſuch, in doubt leſt the ſame ſhould be offenſiuely reported to vs: We haue thought it conuenient aſwell for the ſatiſfaction of the one ſort, as for admonition to the others, to publiſh by open ſignification, That ſeeing it hath pleaſed Almightie God to call vs to the Supreme power ouer both, Wee are purpoſed to be an vniuerſall and equall Souereigne to them both, and to adminiſter Iuſtice where there ſhall be oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion, without any worldly reſpect to either of them. And therefore doe hereby enioyne all Lieutenants, Deputy Lieutenants, Iuſtices of Peace, and all other our Officers and Miniſters of this Kingdome, that whenſoeuer com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint ſhall be made to any of them, that breach of Peace is committed by thoſe of our Nation of Scotland, vpon the Subiects of England, or by the Subiects of England vpon thoſe of the Nation of Scotland, In both which kindes we heare of many great abuſes, though ſometimes aggrauated according to the humour of the Reporters, they ſhall carefully vpon euery complaint, examine with all indifferency the particulars of euery ſuch Action, and cauſe puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to be inflicted vpon the partie offending, without reſpect of Nation, according to the Lawes of this Realme.</p>
            <p>And to the end they may not doubt ot proceede to the execution thereof: As we doe hereby not onely aſſure them that we will ſtrengthen and maintaine all Officers and Magiſtrates in the execution of their Officers, for the preſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uation of the publike Peace of this Realme: So if we ſhall ſee at any time that any Magiſtrate ſhal be ſlow to redreſſe ſuch grieuances, or puniſh the Offenders, We ſhall haue cauſe to thinke, that they are willing to nouriſh ſome cauſe of ſuch rumours, the rather to ſerue for colour or cauſe of further alienantion, &amp; ſo by conſequence of ſedition amongſt our people, and an hinderance to that union betweene both States, which is one of the greateſt benefits that We bring with vs to our people for their ſtrength and ſafetie; in gouerning of whom, though We muſt vſe, as all other Princes doe, the miniſtery of ſubodinate Miniſters, yet God Almighty knoweth, that in our owne mind there is not a thought of partialitie towards either of them, but an internal deſire and reſolution to afford indifferent Grace and Iuſtice to all: For demonſtration whereof We haue bene forced to publiſh thus much, leſt the iniquitie of Faction and vnruly ſpirits might blemiſh the innocencie and intergritie of our heart towards all our Subiects, whom We holde dearer then our owne life.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at our Castle of Windſore<date>the eight day of Iuly, 1603. in the firſt yeere of our Reigne of England, France, and Ireland, And of Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land the ſixe and thirtieth.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at Lodon by Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie.</p>
            <p>ANNO DOM. 1603.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
